Killian Jochen McShane

Computer Science Student



Third-year student of computer science at The University of Liverpool, specialising in artificial intelligence and data science. Proficient in Python, R, Java, SQL, and functional Haskell programming languages with experience using software development and data analysis tools such as Apache Ant, Power BI and Tableau. I am highly IT and Mathematically literate, with a strong background in customer-facing roles.

Education

BSc (Hons) Computer Science with Artificial Intelligence The University of Liverpool

09/2018 - Present

First Class (Expected)

Career

Data Analyst

The Walton Centre NHS Trust

10/2021 - Present

Liverpool

- Developing predictive modelling, clinical and patient flow algorithms for statistical data analysis.
- Providing actionable insight to recommend opportunities and improvements through analytics with SQL & Power BI.

Customer Service Representative

The Royal Bank of Scotland

10/2017 - 03/2018

Belfast

- High-pressure environment with heavy call queues. Teamwork, exceeding KPI expectations and preventing escalations was necessary to succeed.
- Asking pertinent questions and empathetically delivering help was key to resolving issues quickly.

Customer Service Representative

Teleperformance UK

10/2016 - 04/2017

Newry

- Handled and managed customer complaints.
- Clarified payment options and credit management.

Data Analysis Spring Internship

FM Environmental

04/2015

Newry

- Analysed and processed friction and fluid calculations.
- Graphed insights from data analysis using Excel to relay information to engineers.

Languages

• English

Native or Bilingual Proficiency

German

Professional Working Proficiency

Skills



Achievements

Founder & President of The Data Science and Artificial Intelligence Society at The University of Liverpool

I manage the society. My leadership involves chairing meetings, attracting funding, and managing relationships with stakeholders.

University of Liverpool Leadership Programme (2021)

Attended the university's leadership programme to boost my leadership potential and develop my professional skills.

BT Young Scientist Boot Camp (2015)

Selected for and won the competition. Lead a team of 5 individuals through the development lifecycle of a new product.

Interests

Boxing	Running		Mathe	ematics
Deep Learning		Big Data		Crypto & Blockchain

Projects

 Dissertation Project: A.I. for Political Sentiment Classification (Python, Google Colab)

Using Google's BERT natural language processing machine learning model and various social media APIs, I plan to web-scrape a dataset of political comments and classify them by their political leaning.

- Automated Build Deployment & Testing (Java)
 Build deployment using Apache Ant, Java, XML build file, and JUnit.
- Short-term Stock Price Prediction Web-app (Python, JS)

Stock price prediction using an LSTM Neural Network, Twitter's API and natural language processing, sentiment analysis of Tweets.

...and many more on my GitHub portfolio.